

SALVADOR ROCHA

Software Developer

PROFILE

Senior Developer, experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web and desktop projects. Working with numerous programming languages like Javascript, C#, Go, Java as well as the Frameworks like React, Angular, Vue.

CONTACT ME

Birthdate November 1986 México, Aguascalientes, Aguascalientes

https://chavita.info srochar86@hotmail.com

SKILLS

Lead, Project management.
Strong decision maker.
Complex problem solver.
Service-focused.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer, Remote — Freelance

DEC 2020 - Currently

Refactor Home City Ice Mobile App moving from Expo to React Native CLI, implemented Stripe payments with Credit/Debit Cards and ACH charges. Migrate Internal Mobile App from React Native 0.60 to 0.64 removing all the expo dependencies, implemented and integrated redux toolkit library with redux-saga.

Created a web Education Platform to connect tutors with parents, creating an API REST with NodeJs (express), in the frontend React connected with firebase to implement a realtime chat and deploy it on a Heroku dyno.

Frontend Developer, Remote — Search Rebel

APR 2019 - AUG 2020

Develop React (NextJs) components for a low-code no-code platform connected with an API with Neo4j and Java. Components like recursive menus, trees, etc. Customizable with the json file.

Backend Sr. Freelance, Aguascalientes — C3 ENG - Nissan Company OCT 2018 - DEC 2018

Refactor Client-Server application (C# .NET) to read data from Nissan System and save it to our Database in SQL Server to control torque wrench in the assembly line, removing crashing issues provoked by sockets and threads.

Full Stack Developer, Aguascalientes — *CRISA / Linea Italia* NOV 2016 - JUL 2018

Full Stack developer, create web applications with C# .NET and Vue, React, SQL Server like to control invoices, orders, and other different internal processes for the company. Development service communication between Dynamics and Prestashop systems. I also configured a server with PHP7, MariaDB, Apache over CentOS in Digital Ocean.

Senior Developer, Aguascalientes — *INBLAY - Nissan Company* MAR 2016 - MAY 2016

Develop web application with C# .NET to handle internal control processes (read data from external system and implement sockets to handle the connection between both applications then save data in Databases). Improved front end template for all the web systems with vanilla JS.

Freelance, Aguascalientes — *Government of Aguascalientes* JAN 2014 - OCT 2015

Develop web applications with C# .NET, one of them a financial system which allowed full control of loans, another one a customizable CMS with .NET MVC, SQL Server and Javascript.

Head of Systems Department, Aguascalientes — *City Hall* JAN 2013 - DEC 2014

Lead department with 20 members to develop and maintenance new applications with C# .NET and SQL Server around 13 web, desktops applications,

change some systems from VB6 to C# .NET many of these for efficiency problems.

EDUCATION

English Level 5, Aguascalientes — *Berlitz* JAN 2018 - MAR 2019

Degree IT and Networking, Aguascalientes — *Instituto Tecnológico de Aguascalientes* AUG 2004 - JAN 2010

Computer Technician, Aguascalientes — CETIS #155 AUG 2001 - JUL 2003

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS & LANGUAGE SKILLS

Professional Skills

- Javascript (good)
- C# .NET (good)
- Java (prior experience)
- Go (good)
- Python (basic)
- SQL (fluent)
- NoSQL (basic)

Language Skills

Spanish (native)

English (intermediate)